Career Services Records UA107
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Career Services Records
1969 -- 2011
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Career Services
UA107
0.21 Linear Feet 1 box
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into one series: Subject files.
Scope and Contents
The collection contains pamphlets and fliers produced by the Career Services office as well as memoranda and a newspaper article dating from 1969-1999. In addition, there are Placement Manuals, Placement Handbooks, and weekly newsletters called Career News.
Biographical / Historical
Career Services (1900-present) was established in 1900 by the Alumni Council and the Trustees of the College and was originally called the Placement Bureau. The Bureau functioned as a clearinghouse and referral agency for graduating students. The Office name went through many changes, starting with the Employment Bureau (Tufts College Catalog 1921-22, 47). Revived in 1929 as the Placement Bureau (Light on the Hill, 435). In 1933, it became the Department of Personnel and Vocational Guidance. The department's new scope included hiring a psychologist to help students with orientation, studying, mental hygiene and other issues. Freshman counseling was established in this office in 1936-1937 school year and became permanent. The Committee on Student Employment was also established in 1936, and its services were designed to help undergraduate students find part-time jobs. In tandem with this, a Placement Office was created for alumni in 1936 (Light on the Hill, 658).
The office was first located in Ballou Hall, then moved to Eaton Memorial Hall in the 1920s. From 1973-1987, the office was called Career Guidance and Placement and was located in Bolles Hall, 226 College Ave., Medford, MA (Facilities Management, UA021/001). From 1987-1999, the office was called Career Planning Center, with a shortening to Career Planning in 1990. In 1999, the name was changed to Career Services and was moved to the Dowling Hall Student Services Center, 419 Boston Ave., Medford, MA.
The Career Services Office is administered by the Division of Student Services, which is overseen by the Office of the Dean of Student Affairs.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Student Affairs and Services; Alumni and Alumni Relations
- Subject files, 1969 -- 2011; UA107.001; 0.25 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains subject files of the Career Services office dating from 1969 to 1999. It consists of pamphlets and fliers produced by the Career Services office as well as memoranda and a newspaper article. In addition, there are Placement Manuals, Placement Handbooks, and a weekly newsletter called Career News.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - [Career News Published by Career Guidance and Placement Tufts University], 1978 -- 1982; UA107.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
    It was published weekly.
  - [Interimships and Internship Program at Tufts], 1995 -- 1999; UA107.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - [Memorandum and Tufts Undergraduate Placement in Graduate Schools], 1972 -- 1974; UA107.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - [Job-Seeking Doctors will Find Help at Tufts], 1977; UA107.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
    Newspaper Clipping
  - [Pamphlets and Fliers from the Career Guidance and Placement Office], 1979; UA107.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
    Folder is unordered.
  - [Placement Handbook Tufts University], 1969 -- 1971; UA107.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - [Placement Manual], 1975 -- 1984; UA107.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - [Tufts Career Advisory Network], 1997; UA107.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - [Tufts University Employees Safety Handbook], 1982; UA107.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - [Life After School Explained], 2007; UA107.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - [Tufts Career Advisory Network flyer], 2011; UA107.001.001.00011 (Box 1)